MEEGAN ANDERSON

Chicago, IL

Phone: 630-728-2730 | Email: meegan.r.anderson@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>@meegan-r-anderson</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/NotANewt</u> Portfolio: <u>https://meegan-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/</u>

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with 15 years of background in Science and Data Analysis. Enjoys the logic, creativity, and problem solving involved in building user-friendly applications. Currently honing my front end skills through a Front End internship and recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from Northwestern University, Chicago, IL.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript, SQL(MySQL, NoSQL), and IDL

Libraries: React

Frameworks: Next.js, Bootstrap, Bulma, Node.js, Handlebars.js, Express, Mongoose, and JQuery **Software:** VSCode, GitHub, GitLab, MySQL Workbench, Studio 3T, Figma, Storyboard, GSuite, and

Microsoft Office

MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Organization: Task Delegation, Staff Organization, Inventory Management **Training:** Onboarding, Safety, Laboratory Protocols, and Data Analysis

ADMINISTRATION SKILLS

Manuscripts: Editing and Proofreading **Finances:** Invoices and Reimbursements

Purchasing: Requesting Quotes, Placing Order Requests, Tracking Orders, Receiving Orders

PROJECTS

Pick A Flick | https://github.com/NotANewt/pick_a_flick | https://tinyurl.com/mr2hhcsm

- A website to help a group of friends choose a movie to watch together employing user input, anonymous veto, and a final random movie selection
- Tools/Languages Used: React, GraphQL with a Node.js and Express.js server, MongoDB, authentication (JWT), Bcrypt, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML5

PetLink | https://github.com/GET-POST-malone/project_2 | https://tinyurl.com/42kd8ju9

- An owner-to-owner rehoming pet application where users can search for adoptable pets as well as add a pet to rehome.
- Project Lead: Worked on the JavaScript and handlebars for the Pet Search page as well as organizing and solving issues with routes and general code cleanup throughout app.
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bulma, Handlebars.js, and SQL

Tech Talk | https://github.com/NotANewt/tech_blog | https://tinyurl.com/2p8r3cz6

- A CMS-style blog where developers can publish blog posts, view and comment on existing posts, update and delete their posts, and delete comments on their posts.
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, and SQL

EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer Intern Foxtrot

June, 2022 – Present Chicago, IL

Responsibilities: Build components and pages, handle bug tickets, and learn the code base for Foxtrot's React Next.js website

Key Accomplishments:

- Built a Wifi Landing Page for Foxtrot's website where users enter their email to connect to the local wifi and are sent to a page showing trending items at their local store
- Currently building Cafe Pickup app for Foxtrot's website to mimic Foxtrot's mobile apps, allowing users to select and pre-pay for items to pick up at their local store
- Manager impressed with the speed at which I learned and implemented new skills

Senior Laboratory Technologist Northwester University - Hope Lab

September 2017 – Present Chicago, IL

Responsibilities: IDL, data analysis, project management, project planning, delegation, safety regulation paperwork and oversight, safety training, protocol training, onboarding of new hires, manuscript writing/editing, purchasing, and inventory management.

Team Size: 15 to 30 lab members

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted from Laboratory Technologist 3 to take on managerial tasks from an overloaded laboratory manager
- Outstanding Annual Reviews

Laboratory Technologist 3 Northwester University - Hope Lab

September 2008 – September 2017

Chicago, IL

Responsibilities: Data analysis of virion particles, cell types, and properties of moving particles in samples, project planning, IDL, data analysis, paper writing/editing, and preparation of regulatory documents

Team Size: 20 to 30 lab members

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted from Laboratory Technologist 1 to be involved in more diverse projects and increased responsibility.
- Included in the team tasked with learning and utilizing IDL

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp: Northwestern University, Chicago, IL A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Master of Arts in Biological Anthropology: University of Colorado at Boulder, Boulder, CO Field Research for Master's Thesis in Hanoi, Vietnam: Evaluated the variation in cranial anatomy of the cercopithecids in Vietnam. Organized data collection with two undergraduate assistants to take measurements from a large collection.

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science with supplemental major in Anthropology: University of Notre Dame, IN